A Finding Aid to the William Penhallow Henderson Papers, 1876-1987, bulk 1876-1943, in the Archives of American Art AAA.hendwill
Archives of American Art
- Artwork, 1886-1929; Series 11; 1.9 Linear feet Boxes 6-8, OV 14
  - Artwork by Others, 1910-1911, undated (Box 8)
    - Japanese Prints, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Japanese Prints, undated (Box OV 14)
- Printed Material, 1891-1988; Series 12; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 8-9
  Printed material primarily consists of loose clippings, a scrapbook of clippings, and exhibition announcements and catalogs. There are also press releases, programs, and brochures and booklets on miscellaneous topics.
  - Clippings, 1891-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 13-71)
  - Scrapbook of Clippings, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1904-1913 (Box 8, Folder 73-78)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1914-1987 (Box 9, Folder 1-24)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1927-1931 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Album of Reproductions of Artwork by Henderson, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Others, undated (Box 9, Folder 27-30)
  - Press Releases, 1963-1978 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Programs, 1906-1916 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Brochures, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Booklets, 1927, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1927-1940, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Picture Postcards, undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Photographs, 1887-1985; Series 13; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 9-11, 13
  Photographs are of Henderson, his family, and friends including American Indians Elias Suazo and Klah, stunt riders, an expedition by horseback through the mountains, and Henderson's trip to a mine. Photographs of Henderson's architectural projects, include his own homes in Lake Bluff, Illinois, and Santa Fe, New Mexico. Henderson also was the architect of the White Residence, McComb Garden, Railroad Ticket Office, and the Otis Residence, all in Santa Fe. There are also photographs of exhibitions and of artwork by Henderson and others. The albums of photographs of artwork were assembled by Henderson's daughter, Alice Henderson Rossin. Additional photographs may be found in the Project Files and Furniture Files.
  - Photographs of Henderson, 1887-1840 (Box 9, Folder 37-40)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 1.
  - Photographs of Family Members, 1920s (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Friends, 1919-1937 (Box 9, Folder 42-46)
  - Photographs of the House in Lake Bluff, Illinois, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Photographs of Henderson's Studio in Santa Fe, 1919-1922 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Photographs of Henderson's House "Hen-Cor" in Santa Fe, 1924-1934 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Photographs of Trip to Mine, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Photographs of the White Residence, 1924-1929 (Box 9, Folder 51-58)
  - Photographs of the McComb Garden, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 2.
  - Photographs of the Railroad Ticket Office, Santa Fe, 1926-1927 (Box 10, Folder 4-7)
  - Photographs of the Otis Residence, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Rodin's House, Paris, France, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Architecture, 1916, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of an Exhibition at Art Institute of Chicago, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of an Exhibition at Fonda Gallery, Santa Fe, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of an Exhibition at New York Architectural League, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of the Opening of Exhibition "Master Colorist of Santa Fe" at Phoenix Art Museum, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  - Photographs of the Opening of Exhibition "Master Colorist of Santa Fe" at Museum of Western Art, Denver, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 16-18)
  - Albums of Photographs of Artwork, 1963, undated (Box 10, Folder 19-22)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 3.
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Artwork by Henderson, 1970-1981, undated (Box 11, Folder 1-16)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 4.
  - Photographs of Set and Costume Designs for Alice in Wonderland, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Henderson's Murals Commissioned by Frank Lloyd Wright for Midway Gardens, Chicago, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Photographs of a Santa Fe Billboard Design, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Architectural Drawings and Models by Henderson, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Photographs of Artwork by Others, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Photographs of Artwork by American Indians, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Oversized Photograph of Henderson with his Hockey Team, 1892 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Photograph of Henderson with an Unidentified American Indian, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Photographs of the McComb Garden, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Album of Photographs of Artwork by Henderson, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Photographs of Miscellaneous Artwork by Henderson, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)